Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/adeleofficial (LinkedIn) adele.com/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Singing

Pianist

Guitarist

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards

Best Original Song (Skyfall)
Favorite Adult Contemporary Artist
Favorite Pop/Rock Female Artist
Favorite Pop/Rock Album (21)
Favorite Adult Contemporary Artist

Adele Adkins

Singer, Songwriter at XL Recordings London, England Metropolitan Area

Summary

Adele Laurie Blue Adkins is an English singer-songwriter. After graduating from the BRIT School in 2006, Adele signed a recording contract with XL Recordings. In 2007, she received the Brit Awards Critics' Choice Award and won the BBC Sound of 2008 poll. Her debut album, 19, was released in 2008 to commercial and critical success. It is certified eight times platinum in the UK, and three times platinum in the US. The album contains her first song, "Hometown Glory", written when she was 16, which is based on her home suburb of West Norwood in London. An appearance she made on Saturday Night Live in late 2008 boosted her career in the US. At the 51st Grammy Awards in 2009, Adele received the awards for Best New Artist and Best Female Pop Vocal Performance.

Adele released her second studio album, 21, in 2011. The album was critically well received and surpassed the success of her debut, earning numerous awards in 2012, among them a record-tying six Grammy Awards, including Album of the Year; two Brit Awards, including British Album of the Year; and three American Music Awards, including Favorite Pop/Rock Album. The album has been certified 17 times platinum in the UK, and is overall the fourth bestselling album in the nation. In the US, it has held the top position longer than any album since 1985, and is certified diamond. The best-selling album worldwide of 2011 and 2012, 21 has sold over 31 million copies. The success of 21 earned Adele numerous mentions in the Guinness Book of World Records. She was the first female artist to simultaneously have two albums in the top five of the Billboard 200 and two singles in the top five of the Billboard Hot 100, as well as the first woman in the history of the Billboard Hot 100 to have three simultaneous top 10 singles as a lead artist, with "Rolling in the Deep", "Someone Like You", and "Set Fire to the Rain", all of which also topped the chart. 21 is the longest-running number one album by a female solo artist in the history of the UK and US Album Charts.

Source: Wikipedia

Experience

XL Recordings Singer 2008 - Present (12 years) London, England, United Kingdom

Columbia Records Singer 2012 - 2012 (less than a year)

Education

BRIT School

Performing Arts and Technology · (1995 - 2006)